<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on pstwh</title><link>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on pstwh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Paulo Alves</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pstwh.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are you ready?</title><link>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/are-you-ready/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/are-you-ready/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine the first human unable to beat a machine. How did they feel?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the obvious:&lt;br>
AI systems will inevitably exceed human capabilities in every domain. They&amp;rsquo;ll be faster, more efficient, and their operational costs will be minimal—essentially just energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="machines">Machines&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Whether current AI systems will reach this level remains to be seen, but they are showing promising signs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How will people react when they are consistently outperformed by machines?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lightweight License Plate Reading with Custom OCR</title><link>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/license-plates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:25:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/license-plates/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="idea">Idea&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Several months ago, I conceived a project and brought it to fruition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core idea was to develop a lightweight, custom Optical Character Recognition (OCR) system for reading license plates, specifically Brazilian ones. This system needed to be fast enough to run efficiently on a smartphone, operate offline (eliminating the need for a server), and ultimately support a mobile application. The app would capture images of passing vehicles, recognize their license plates, and send the extracted data to an API.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There is no better time than now</title><link>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/hello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 13:39:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://pstwh.github.io/posts/hello/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is no better time than now&lt;br>
To seize the day, to take the plow&lt;br>
And do what must be done&lt;br>
Before our time is done&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The clock ticks on, with no pause&lt;br>
And time will not wait for us to pause&lt;br>
So let us act, with all our might&lt;br>
Before it&amp;rsquo;s too late, and we take flight&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world is ours to shape and mold&lt;br>
But only if we are bold&lt;br>
So let us rise, and claim our place&lt;br>
Before our time runs out, and we face&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>